Amina Michuki

Kenya



michukiamina@yahoo.com



linkedin.com/in/amina-michuki-7b487b5a

Summary

5+years experience in internal & external communications, events planning, drafting communications materialsnewsletters, and managing company websites. Delivered over 40 presentations and video conferencing meetings for 200+ staff.

A team player (since I want to not only go fast but far as well), adaptable to change (the only thing constant in this world is change, best to embrace this) and fast learner(life is a university without graduation, everyday is a lesson). I aim for excellence and work to attain more than the set objectives.

Specialties:

Events management

Website management

Generation of communications materials for both internal and external stakeholders

Writing- news articles, feature stories, newsletters

Digital media usage

Creative design

Find more detailed information in the experience section below or just drop me a message, I will pleasantly respond.

Experience



Director, Communications and Digital Marketing

C&C Designs Ltd

Aug 2020 - Present (2 months +)

Creative and Collective Designs (C&C Designs) is a tech company that focuses on providing creative graphic designs, innovative and interactive web design and development as well as up to date trends and engaging digital marketing strategies.

With a background in Communications and Digital Marketing, I am responsible for the Corporate Affairs, Internal Communications and Digital Marketing, which provides strategic support functions to C & C Designs. These functions include brand visibility & management, social media engagement, internal communication, stakeholder management and corporate image management.

I have a wealth of communications professional experience spanning over 5 years in various organisations, including Kenya News Agency as a Print Journalist Intern, Green Screen Productions as a translator and video editing intern, Bamburi Cement as a Communications Assistant and Geocad Services Limited as a Digital Media Specialist.

I joined C & C Designs as the Communications and Digital Marketing Director from August 2020.



Geocad Services Limited

Mar 2020 - Present (7 months +)

Geocad Services Limited is a local company made up of Geospatial engineers who seek to provide solutions to individuals as well as business. The solutions range from Engineering survey, cadastral survey, topographical survey, hydrographical survey, Geographical Informations Systems and digital mapping.

I provide Geocad with digital solutions that include website development and management, social media management, SEO expertise as well as content creation for their blog and graphics design for their communications. The social media marketing strategy is also part of the work that I am doing for the organisation.

Communications Assistant

Bamburi Cement Ltd

Aug 2015 - Aug 2020 (5 years 1 month)

Bamburi Cement Ltd (A Member of LafargeHolcim) is one of the leading cement manufacturing companies in Kenya.

I assist the organisation by:

- ~ Engaging with external stakeholders organisation of stakeholder and staff luncheons since 2017 to help create and nurture a relationship between staff and stakeholders. This allowed to put a face to the people we interacted with and smooth over issues that each party had to the aid of the business
- ~ Event management- organisation of staff participation in Beyond Zero, Standard Chartered, Ndakaini marathons since 2015 to date, organisation of Beaujolais Nouveau festival in Kenya every year since 2015, preparation and coordination of Town hall meetings every quarter, planning and organising of End of year party, since 2015,
- ~ Internal communication- compiling and publishing of internal newsletters, sending out internal communications, filing documents, photography of events since 2015 for over 200 staff in Mombasa and Nairobi. I have generate several types of newsletters
- ~ Website management updating, managing and generating content of Lafarge.co.ke website, the company website since 2015. Knowledge of Content Management Systems like Drupal, WYSIWYG, Joomla, and WordPress have helped me accomplish this task efficiently.
- ~ Social Media Management- assisting in brainstorming ideas for the pages, content creation, editing & posting. Knowledge of publishing tools like Buffer, Hootsuite & Media monitoring reports analysis was helpful in running successful pages.
- ~ Handling CSR activities of the company- organised staff visits to children's homes in Nairobi to give back to the community since 2015. I also assisted in donations and sponsorship of CSR projects that saw construction of a Cancer Centre in Mombasa Hospital, construction of Boreholes, classrooms in various schools in Kisumu, Kitui among others, as well as paving of Machakos Institute for the Blind pathways to assist the students with easy movement



Intern

Afrokids

Dec 2014 - May 2015 (6 months)

A blogger for Afromum a site under the company Afrokids. The site was about lifestyle, technology, opinion and parenting.

I helped in:

- ~ Gathering information on various topics like daycare centres need to know to help working mother
- ~ Attending of events and summarising the need to know items for a working mother as well as where to get what they need at affordable prices
- ~ Analysis of the products and reviewing them to ease the working mother load of finding products that would be good to use and which would be harmful
- ~ Creation of content on the website with the Content Management System- WordPress.
- ~ Management of social media pages- Afromum with the assistance of publishing tools like Buffer and Hootsuite.



Intern

Green Screen Productions

Nov 2013 - Dec 2013 (2 months)

Green Screens Production is a movie production studio based in Mombasa. It produces local movies promoting local artists and content. My duties and responsibility was;

- ~ Assist in editing the movies that had been produced using Adobe Premier Pro and Avid
- ~ Assist in translation from Kiswahili to English language
- ~Transcribing subtitles for the movies
- ~ Assist in voice recording of voice overs for the movies



Intern

Kenya News Agency

Sep 2013 - Oct 2013 (2 months)

Kenya News Agency specializes in news gathering and dissemination countrywide and beyond with emphasis on development news. My duties were:

- ~ Collecting news worthy stories in Mombasa like the elections results after the court sessions to contend the electoral results of certain wards
- ~ Dissemination of the news through social media pages of the agency
- ~ Talking to the communities to generate a rapport with them for feature stories on what goes on in the county

Education



Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Bachelor of science in Mass in Communication, Mass Communication/Media Studies 2011 - 2014

Majored in Broadcast Journalism, I got skills in digital media, broadcasting, photography, videography and video editing using Adobe Premier pro.



Alliance Française de Mombasa

N/A, French Language and Literature 2011 - 2011

Got beginners training on the French language that allowed me to have a cultural understanding of the French culture. Took part in the after school French cultural trainings run by the director. These sessions allowed us to practise speaking French, pushed me to expand my vocabulary and pronunciation.

Licenses & Certifications



Reaching Customers Digitally - Skillsoft



Coding Intro - IBM

Skills

Microsoft Office • Microsoft Word • Editing • PowerPoint • Customer Service • Microsoft Excel • Public Speaking • Outlook • English • Windows